Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Public Affairs Department Records 1945-2000 (bulk 1959-1996) MS 3009-RG 19
New-York Historical Society
- Series VIII. General Files, 1945-1999; 221830; 26.5 Linear feet (26 boxes, 35 reels of microfilm)
  - Subseries VIII.A. Administrative Files, 1963-1989; 221729; 18 Linear feet (18 boxes)
    - Fortune: Advertising, 1979-1980; 221779 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 6)
    - Fortune: Circulation, 1987; 221780 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 7)
    - Fortune: Edit Information, 1977; 221781 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 8)
    - Fortune: Facts, 1983; 221782 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 9)
    - Fortune: First Cover Photo (copy), undated; 221783 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 10)
    - Fortune: International, 1982; 221784 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 11)
    - Fortune: Press Releases, 1977-1987; 221785 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 12)
    - Fortune: Publicity, 1982; 221786 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 13)
    - Grunwald, Henry: Biography, 1984-1987; 221787 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 14)
    - Grunwald, Henry: Speeches, 1969-1985; 221788 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 15-16)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): General Information, 1974-1982 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 7-9)
      Includes promotional material, a handbook on pay television, and press releases.
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Affiliate Services, circa 1982 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 10)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Articles, 1977-1984 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 11-12)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): AT&T, 1981; 221789 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 17)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Audience Research, 1982 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 13)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Censorship, 1983 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 14)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): CBS and Columbia Joint Venture Press Release and Q&A, 1983 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 15)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Columbia Pictures Industry, Inc. and Tri-Star Pictures Renegotiation, 1985 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 16)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): First Amendment Information Kit, 1983; 221790 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 18)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Getty Oil Company and Premier Lawsuit, 1981 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 17)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Inside HBO: George Mair book, 1985 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 18)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Los Angeles Times Corporate Profile of HBO, 1983 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 19)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Obscenity, 1983 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 20)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Personnel, 1977-1984 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 21)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Photographs of People at Work, circa 1980 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 22)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Press Releases, 1980-1986; 221791 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 19-24)
    - Home Box Office (HBO): Statement on Joint Venture by Four Movies Companies and Getty Oil Company, 1980 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 23)
    - International Paper: Striking Workers' Letters, 1987 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 3-4)
    - Magazine Development Fact Sheet, 1984-1987; 221792 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 25)
    - Magazine Group Forums, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 25)
    - Magazine Issues (Newsletter of the Magazine Group), 1987; 221793 (Offsite-box 1752, Folder 26-28)
    - Magazines: General, 1974-1987; 221794 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 1)
    - Magazines: Advertising, 1969-1988 (Offsite-box 2507, Folder 24)
    - Magazines: Fact Sheet, 1983-1988 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 1-2)
    - Magazines: Max Plan, 1987 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 3)
    - Magazines: Press Releases, 1980-1981; 221795 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 2)
    - Manhattan Cable: Articles On, 1973-1989 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 4)
    - Manhattan Cable: Press Clippings, 1976-1986 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Cable: Press Releases, 1980 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 6)
    - Manhattan Cable: Programming, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 7)
    - Manhattan Cable At Work, circa 1980 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 8)
    - Money: Awards, 1976-1987; 221796 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 3)
    - Money: Edit Information, 1977; 221797 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 4)
    - Money: Fact Sheet, 1981-1983; 221798 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 5)
    - Money: House Organs List, 1979; 221799 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 6)
    - Money: Logo, undated; 221800 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 7)
    - Money: Press Releases, 1978-1988; 221801 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 8)
    - Money: Reprints, 1976; 221802 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 9)
    - Money: Speakers, 1976; 221803 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 10)
    - Moral Rights in Berne Copyright Convention, 1987; 221804 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 11-12)
    - Moral Rights in Berne Copyright Convention [RESTRICTED], 222008 (Offsite-box R25)
    - New York Magazine Piece on Magazine Development, 1984 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 5)
    - "New York Perspectives" Series, 1976-1979 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 6-7)
    - Nexis, 1983-1984; 221805 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 13-14)
    - Pay-Per-View Network, 1987; 221806 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 15)
    - Personnel: Head Count, 1978-1981; 229578 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 1)
    - Picture Policy Statement, 1977-1982; 221807 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 16)
    - Pioneer Press, 1969-1984; 229579 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 2)
    - PR Aids Bills and Orders, 1987-1989; 229580 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 3-5)
    - Press Releases, 1982-1985 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 9-11)
    - Press Releases, 1987; 229581 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 6-7)
    - Silver Screen Pictures, 1983-1984; 221808 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 17)
    - Society Pages of New York Times, 1980 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 12)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Cave, Ray, 1985; 229582 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 8)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Daniel, Carlyle C., 1983; 229584 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 9)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Davidson, Ralph P., 1980-1987; 229586 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 10-17)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Greene, Susan, 1985; 229587 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 18)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Grunwald, Henry, 1987; 229589 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 19)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Guttman, William, 1984; 229590 (Offsite-box 2101, Folder 20)
      Includes notes on the Gabe Perlman roast.
    - Speeches and Remarks: Heiskell, Andrew, 1966-1986; 229593 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 1-4)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Heyworth, James O., 1983; 229594 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 5)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Hiland, Bruce, 1985; 229595 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 6)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Kelly, William, 1983; 229596 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 7)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Luftman, Michael, 1985; 229597 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 8)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Manley, Joan, 1986; 229598 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 9)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Meyers, John A., 1968; 229599 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 10)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Myhren, Trygve, 1981; 229600 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 11)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Thomas, Richard B., 1982; 229601 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 12)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Torello, Judy, 1986; 229602 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 13)
    - Speeches and Remarks: Wilson, Donald, 1985; 229603 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 14)
    - Spinoff Articles, 1983 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 13)
    - Sports Illustrated: Advertising, undated; 221810 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 18)
    - Sports Illustrated: Press Releases, 1977-1989; 221809 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 19)
    - Stock Listing on New York Stock Exchange (NYSE), 1964; 221811 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 20-21)
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1970-1975; 221812 (Offsite-box 1753, Folder 22-28)
      Materials from the annual meetings include briefing books, questions and answers, display material, press invitations, photographs of the meetings, and special meeting information.
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1975-1979; 221813 (Offsite-box 1754)
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1979-1982; 221834 (Offsite-box 1755, Folder 1-16)
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1981-1983 (Offsite-box 2508, Folder 9-22)
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings, 1983-1987 (Offsite-box 2509)
    - Stockholders Annual Meetings [RESTRICTED], 1979; 222009 (Offsite-box R25)
    - Stockholders Approve Time's Acquisition of Temple, 1973; 221835 (Offsite-box 1755, Folder 17)
    - Subscription Television (STV), 1982-1983; 221836 (Offsite-box 1755, Folder 18)
    - Teletext, 1980-1983; 221837 (Offsite-box 1755, Folder 19-21)
    - Time: Ad Rate Cards, 1981; 221839 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 1)
    - Time: Adler, Renata, 1986; 221841 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 2-3)
    - Time: Advertising, 1977-1981; 221844 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 4)
    - Time: Anniversaries, 1963-1983; 221843 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 5)
    - Time: Newstours, 1981-1985; 221847 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 6)
    - Time: Olympics, 1988; 221848 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 7)
    - Time: Prospectus 1922 (copy), undated; 221849 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 8)
    - Time: Publicity, 1982; 221850 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 9)
    - Time: "Technology and the Making of a Magazine": Special Ad Section, 1986; 221851 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 10)
    - Time: Timeaid: Mexican Earthquake Relief, 1985; 221852 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 11)
    - Time Canada, 1974-1984; 221853 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 12-14)
    - Time Inc. Anti-Trust Conference, 1979 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 14-15)
    - Time Inc. and Matsushita Electric, 1982; 221855 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 15-19)
      Regarding the companies' agreement to co-develop hardware for use in Time Inc.'s teletext service.
    - Time Inc. in Profile, 1988 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 16)
    - Time Inc.: Press Releases, 1980-1988; 221856 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 20)
    - Time to Read, 1985-1988; 221857 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 21-25)
    - Time-Life Broadcast: General, 1967-1971; 221858 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 26)
    - Time-Life Broadcast: Proposal to Sell to McGraw-Hill, 1970-1972; 221859 (Offsite-box 1756, Folder 27)
    - Time-Life Broadcast: Proposal to Sell to McGraw-Hill [RESTRICTED], 222010 (Offsite-box R25)
    - Time-Life Video, 1970-1987; 221861 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 1-2)
    - Tri-Star Pictures, 1982-1986; 221862 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 3)
    - TV-Cable Week: General, 1982-1983; 229604 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 15-16)
    - TV-Cable Week: Byron, Christopher, 1984; 229605 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 17)
    - TV-Cable Week: Cable Magazine Project Statement and Q&As, 1982; 229606 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 18-19)
    - TV-Cable Week: Cable TV Q&As, 1982; 229607 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 20)
    - TV-Cable Week: Closedown, 1982-1983; 229608 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 21-24)
    - TV-Cable Week: Cover, 1983; 229612 (Offsite-box 2102, Folder 25)
    - TV-Cable Week: Issues, 1983; 229613 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 1)
    - TV-Cable Week: Move to White Plains, 1982; 229614 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 2-6)
    - TV-Cable Week: Press Conference, 1982; 229615 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 7)
    - TV-Cable Week: Press Releases, 1982-1983; 229617 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 8-10)
    - TV-Cable Week: Prospectus, 1983; 229618 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 11)
    - TV-Cable Week: Publicity Plan, 1983; 229619 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 12)
    - TV-Cable Week: Publicity Updates, 1982; 229621 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 13-15)
    - TV-Cable Week: Q&A, 1983; 229625 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 16)
    - TV-Cable Week: Staff Announcement, 1983; 229626 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 17)
    - TV-Cable Week: Suggested Talking Points, 1983; 229628 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 18)
    - The Washington Star, 1978-1981; 229630 (Offsite-box 2103, Folder 19-20)
    - United Satellite Communications, Inc.: American Television and Communications, Inc. and Tele-Communications, Inc. Venture, 1985; 221863 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 4)
    - USA Network, 1981-1987; 221869 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 5)
    - Video: General, 1981; 221870 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 6)
    - Video: Speeches: Vincent, Francis, 1983; 221873 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 7)
    - Video: Transponders, 1981-1983; 221875 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 8)
    - Video Group: Development [empty], undated; 221871 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 9)
    - Video Group: Warner Amex, 1985; 221872 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 10)
    - Videocassettes, 1984; 221876 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 11)
    - Videotext, 1981; 221877 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 12)
    - Visiting Journalists, 1985 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 17)
    - Wall Street Journal (Jonathan Kwitney), 1976 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 18)
    - Weekly Clips: 1988 June 17 (Offsite-box 3295, Folder 19)
  - Subseries VIII.B. Annual Reports, 1945-1969, 1973, 1976, 1978; 221880; 0.75 Linear feet (10 folders)
    Annual Reports contains copies of the annual reports and press releases announcing Time Inc.'s net profits. The 1976 file includes correspondence about the production of the report. The 1978 file has drafts of CEO Andrew Heiskell's statement.
    Organized chronologically based on original order.
    - Annual Reports, 1945-1969, 1973, 1976, 1978 (Offsite-box 1757, Folder 13-23)
  - Subseries VIII.C. Dinner Books, 1979-1987; 221936; 0.2 Linear feet (3 folders)
    Dinner Books contains copies of the booklets published to commemorate the dinners held honoring the outgoing and incoming editors-in-chief of Time Inc. The booklets contain texts of the speeches given at the events.
    Organized chronologically with the transfer form at the front.
    - Transfer to Archives Form, 1981; 221937 (Offsite-box 1758, Folder 1)
    - The Donovan Grunwald Graves Dinner, 1979; 221938 (Offsite-box 1758, Folder 2)
    - The Grunwald McManus Dinner, 1987; 221939 (Offsite-box 1758, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VIII.D. Press Releases, 1965-1978; 221940; 1.5 Linear feet (2 boxes, 3 reels of microfilm)
    Press Releases includes press releases on various divisions and publications of Time Inc. Earlier files were divided by tabs into Corporate, Broadcast, Books, and Time-Life Records. Later files cover Corporate, Time-Life Films, Books, Time-Life Video, publications like Money, and subsidiaries such as Sterling Communications. Press releases from 1975 to 1978 were removed in 1980 and are represented by an out card. Press releases from 1999 to 2000 are on microfilm. The dates refer to the original materials and not the date of microfilm creation.
    - Press Releases, 1965-1969; 221941 (Offsite-box 1758, Folder 4-13)
    - Press Releases, 1970-1978; 221942 (Offsite-box 1759, Folder 1-11)
    - Press Releases, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 3326)
  - Subseries VIII.E. Scrapbooks, 1963-1969; 221943; 0.5 Linear feet (8 folders)
    Scrapbooks contain press releases, copies of correspondence, and news clippings on the subject. The Chicago Time & Life Building scrapbooks include some photographs and architectural drawings.
    - Chicago Time & Life Building, 1967-1968; 221944 (Offsite-box 1759, Folder 12-15)
    - Chicago Time & Life Building, 1969; 221945 (Offsite-box 1759, Folder 16)
    - Time Donation to Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), 1968; 221946 (Offsite-box 1760, Folder 1)
    - Time Newstour of Asia, 1965; 221947 (Offsite-box 1760, Folder 2)
    - Time-Sponsored Newstour of Europe and Soviet Union by U.S. Businessmen, 1963; 221948 (Offsite-box 1760, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VIII.F. Weekly News Clippings, 1970-1999; 221949; 5 Linear feet (5 boxes, 35 reels of microfilm)
    Weekly News Clippings contains packets of copied news clips for distribution regarding magazines, departments, or subsidiaries of Time Inc. Many packets include cover sheets showing they were compiled by Louis Slovinsky.
    Weekly Press Reports are a continuation of the press clippings packets, but on microfilm. The dates refer to the original material and not the date of microfilm creation. Not all months or years within the range are present. Overlapping dates with the physical packets may mean there is some duplication.
    - Weekly News Clippings, 1970-1972; 221950 (Offsite-box 1760, Folder 4-12)
    - Weekly News Clippings, 1972-1973; 221969 (Offsite-box 1761)
    - Weekly News Clippings, 1974-1976; 221970 (Offsite-box 1762)
    - Weekly News Clippings, 1976-1978; 221971 (Offsite-box 1785)
    - Weekly News Clippings, 1978-1979; 221973 (Offsite-box 1786)
    - Weekly Press Reports, 1971-1999 (Offsite-box 3326)